Luciano Abel Sandoval

(+54) 11-24559775 lucianosandoval393@gmail.com github.com/Kuesmar linkedin.com/l-sandoval

Full-Stack (Front-End oriented) developer with 3+ years of experience developing JavaScript, React, NodeJS, HTML5, CSS3 and web applications on a self-employed business. I worked on a small development team delivering end to end applications for different organizations with a variety of projects from web applications to Java distributed management systems. I also had the opportunity to work with agile methodologies such as Scrum and version control systems such as Git.

EXPERIENCE

Syersy Argentina, Founder and Front-End Software Engineer - 2018-2021 (2+ years)

Stack: Full-Stack (Front-End Focus): React.JS, NodeJS, Java, PostgreSQL - Rest-API, Express.JS - Redux - JavaFX. <u>SAMS</u> - 2018-2021 (2+ years)

A Java, JavaFx, CSS and PostgreSQL distributed management software for Songahm Argentina <u>taekwondo</u> organization.

- Reduce loading times by 90% reducing the complexity of Front-End operations and implementing caching for certain API calls.
- Increasing marketing team predictions accuracy by 60% implementing a statistical dashboard that provides graphical information and sales data.
- Improved student's certification time by 40% by integrating the existing software with a React/NodeJS web application to automate the process.
- Helped design and implement a software management system to increase organization control and automate internal processes creating a Java desktop distributed software.

Syersy.com - 2018-2020 1+ years - https://syersy.com

A HTML, CSS, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, and PostgreSQL web application for a self-employed business.

PROJECTS

 $\textbf{Outfit Manager} - 2024 - \underline{\text{https://github.com/Kuesmar/outfitManager/}}$

A small web application using React drag and drop native.

Carrito App- 2024 - https://github.com/Kuesmar/carritoManager/

A web application to emulate a shopping cart.

Stack: HTML, CSS, TypeScript, React.js, Node.js.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Proficient: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3. Familiar: Python, SQL, Java.

Frameworks and Tools: React.js, Redux, Node.js, Express.js, GraphQL, Git, GitHub, Vite, Docker, Bootstrap, Material-UI,

NextUI, React Testing Libraries, Jest, Cypress, Sequelize.

Languages: English, Intermediate; Spanish, Native. Portuguese: Basic.

EDUCATION

UNNE National North-East University – Corrientes, Argentina

Bachelor degree in Information Systems (not finished) Feb 2013 - Dec 2015

Certifications:

EducaciónIT: Javascript Advanced Developer Front-End - Dec 2019

EducaciónIT: Web layout: HTML5 and CSS3 - Oct 2019

EducaciónIT: Java Advanced Programming: Threads, Networking, J2 - Aug 2019

EducaciónIT: *Java Standard Programming, J2SE - Jul 2019* EducaciónIT: *HTML5: Web page fundamentals - Apr 2019*

EducaciónIT: Object Oriented Paradigm introduction - Apr 2019

EducaciónIT: Database and SQL introduction - Feb 2019